<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JMP by women in economics on Asako Mikami</title>
    <link>/series/jmp-by-women-in-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JMP by women in economics on Asako Mikami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/series/jmp-by-women-in-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chelsea E. Carter, &#34;Forts and Frontier: The U.S. Army and the Spatial Distribution of Population&#34;</title>
      <link>/2020/04/18/jmp-review-chelsea-carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/18/jmp-review-chelsea-carter/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is part of my “JMP by Women in Econ” series where I summarize and review some of the job market papers written by women PhD candidates. The papers are selected from Jennifer Doleac’s Twitter thread. I am not reading this from the perspective of an economist, let alone of a job committee member: I just like reading cool articles that use observational data to tackle challenging research problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yi Cheng, &#34;The Unexpected Costs of Expertise: Evidence from Highly Specialized Physicians&#34;</title>
      <link>/2020/04/10/jmp-review-yi-cheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/10/jmp-review-yi-cheng/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is part of my “JMP by Women in Econ” series where I summarize and review some of the job market papers written by women PhD candidates. The papers are selected from Jennifer Doleac’s Twitter thread. I am not reading this from the perspective of an economist, let alone of a job committee member: I just like reading observational studies that tackle challenging research problems.:bowtie:
For my first post of this series, I am reviewing Yi Cheng’s job market paper, “The Unexpected Costs of Expertise: Evidence from Highly Specialized Physicians”(November 4, 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>