<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JMP by Women in Economics on Asako Mikami</title>
    <link>/series/jmp-by-women-in-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JMP by Women in Economics on Asako Mikami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/series/jmp-by-women-in-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CarlyWill Sloan, &#34;Racial Bias by Prosecutors: Evidence from Random Assignment&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/jmp-review-carlywill-sloan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jmp-review-carlywill-sloan/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is coming up during a wave of Black Lives Matter protests in the United States and around the world. Black lives matter. This research paper by CarlyWill Sloan provides evidence on the racism of prosecutors that perpetuates the mass incarceration of Black men.1 Here is an excerpt from the abstract:
 Racial disparities in criminal justice outcomes are well-documented. However, there is little evidence on the extent to which racial bias exhibited by prosecutors is responsible for these disparities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caroline Fry, &#34;Building Bridges: The impact of return migration by African scientists&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/jmp-review-caroline-fry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jmp-review-caroline-fry/</guid>
      <description>The third installment in this series is Caroline Fry’s paper, “Building Bridges: The impact of migration by African scientists.” Here’s an excerpt from the abstract:
 Despite significant interest in the potential for ‘returnee’ scientists moving back to developing countries to connect developed and developing countries, prior work has found limited evidence of success. I shift the focus to the broader network of the returnee, and study the extent to which the return home of American-trained HIV researchers to African institutions impacts publication outcomes of non-migrant scientists in Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chelsea E. Carter, &#34;Forts and Frontier: The U.S. Army and the Spatial Distribution of Population&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/jmp-review-chelsea-carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jmp-review-chelsea-carter/</guid>
      <description>The article I’m reviewing in this blog post is by Chelsea E. Carter, “Forts and Frontier: The U.S. Army and the Spatial Distribution of Population.” The topic is interesting and one I’ve never read about. Moreover, there’s a lot of methodological and computational tools used in this paper, and I was left with a lot of new readings to catch up on.
Me flipping to the reference section
 An excerpt from the abstract:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yi Cheng, &#34;The Unexpected Costs of Expertise: Evidence from Highly Specialized Physicians&#34;</title>
      <link>/posts/jmp-review-yi-cheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jmp-review-yi-cheng/</guid>
      <description>For my first post of the series, “JMP by Women in Economics,” I am reviewing Yi Cheng’s “The Unexpected Costs of Expertise: Evidence from Highly Specialized Physicians”(November 4, 2019). The abstract begins,
 High U.S. spending on health care is commonly attributed to its intensity of specialized, high-tech medical care. A growing body of research focuses on physicians whose medical decisions shape treatment intensity, costs, and patient outcomes. Often overlooked in this research is the assignment of physician skills to patient conditions, which may strongly affect health outcomes and productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>