<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collecting historical weather data on Asako Mikami</title>
    <link>/series/collecting-historical-weather-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collecting historical weather data on Asako Mikami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/series/collecting-historical-weather-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting historical weather data, Part III</title>
      <link>/posts/weather-data-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weather-data-part3/</guid>
      <description>1 Cleaning the data 2 Visualizing the data   To recount, [Part II]({{&amp;lt; ref “/posts/2019-04-18-weather-data-part2” &amp;gt;}}) interpolated the precipitation data we obtained in Part I in order to get county-level precipitation values. Part III (this post) will clean the data further in preparation for the visualization stage and then create a gif animation of chloreoploth maps plotting precipitation level in inches over the seven days leading up to the 2006 midterm election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting historical weather data, Part II</title>
      <link>/posts/weather-data-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weather-data-part2/</guid>
      <description>1 Reproject shapefile 2 Perform Kriging interpolation 3 Reproject raster layer 4 Obtain average total rainfall for each county   prcp_data we created in [Part I]({{&amp;lt; ref “/posts/2019-04-10-weather-data-part1” &amp;gt;}}) is not useful in and of itself because it only shows precipitation values recorded by weather stations. Ultimately, I want to be able to say that county \(i\) for \(i = 1, \ldots, n\) on day \(t\) for \(t = 1, \ldots, T\) had \(x_{it}\) level of precipitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting historical weather data, Part I</title>
      <link>/posts/weather-data-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weather-data-part1/</guid>
      <description>1 Obtain NOAA API key token 2 Obtain weather data with rnoaa::ncdc() 2.1 Code breakdown  3 Obtain weather station data with rnoaa::ncdc_stations() 4 Join dataframes 5 Create spatial point dataframes 6 (Optional) Plot the data   As part of a coauthored project investigating whether rain deters voters from going to the polls in US elections, I had to collect past weather data. This series walks you through how to gather data on the daily total precipitation level from November 1st to November 7th, 2006, where the last day is the 2006 midterm election.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>