<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Asako Mikami</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Asako Mikami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting and parsing tweets, Part III</title>
      <link>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part3/</guid>
      <description>1 Get API key 2 Pass address to Google’s Geocoding API 3 Parse XML 4 if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;   Part II of this tutorial series left us with cleaned&amp;lt;fromHour&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;toHour&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;page-count&amp;gt;.json files. Part III will parse the street addresses in those files and geocode them through Google’s Geocoding API.
Here is the directory tree for Part III:
|-- data/ |-- raw/ # from Part I |-- 01_scraped/ # from Part I |-- 02_cleaned/ # from Part II |-- 03_parsed/ # output for Part III will go here |-- counts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting and parsing tweets, Part II</title>
      <link>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part2/</guid>
      <description>1 Clean the text 2 Find address in the text 3 if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;   Part II will clean the texts and label whether the text contains any street address. Here’s a sketch of the data directory:
|-- data/ |-- raw/ # from Part I |-- 01_scraped/ # from Part I |-- 02_cleaned/ # output for Part II will go here |-- counts.json # from Part I We will use the following packages and set up a logger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting and parsing tweets, Part I</title>
      <link>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/collecting-and-parsing-tweets-part1/</guid>
      <description>1 Open a Twitter developer account 2 OAuth2 authentication 3 Count the number of requests to make 4 Retrieve tweets for every hour 4.1 Make search request 4.2 Scrape the response JSON 4.3 Pull the next page token  5 if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;   This is the first installment of a multi-part series waking through how I used Twitter API to collect, parse, and extract data for my project, “Locates long polling lines with Twitter data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting historical weather data, Part II</title>
      <link>/posts/weather-data-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/weather-data-part2/</guid>
      <description>1 Reproject shapefile 2 Perform Kriging interpolation 3 Reproject raster layer 4 Obtain average total rainfall for each county References   prcp_data we created in Part I is not useful in and of itself because it only shows precipitation values recorded by weather stations. Ultimately, I want to be able to say that county \(i\) for \(i = 1, \ldots, n\) on day \(t\) for \(t = 1, \ldots, T\) had \(x_{it}\) level of precipitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a replication project of Warren (2019)</title>
      <link>/posts/introduce-replicate-warren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/introduce-replicate-warren/</guid>
      <description>I have a project called replicate_warren (a private Github repository), where I am trying to replicate a sociology study, Warren (2019). To put it succinctly, Warren (2019) collected data from résumés of sociology PhD graduates and measured how over-achieving recent PhD graduates had to be to land a junior faculty jobs at top sociology departments in the United States. I want to replicate the study in the political science field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>